Guide to The Women's Sports Foundation Records 1950-2019 (bulk, 1974-2018) MS 3199
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Departmental records, 1971-2018; 146 Linear feet in 146 record cartons
  - Subseries IV.B. Advocacy records, 1971-2006; 16 Linear feet in 16 record cartons
    - Title IX organizations, 1994 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 31)
    - Title IX contact lists, undated (Offsite-box 93, Folder 32)
    - Gender equity resources, 1995-2004 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 33)
    - Title IX publications, 1978-1994 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 1)
    - [Title IX correspondence and news releases], 2002-2004 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 2)
    - Commission/Coalition correspondence, 2002 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 3)
    - Responses to urgent alert, 2003 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 4)
    - Title IX crisis, 2003 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 5)
    - News articles (2 folders), 2003 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 6-7)
    - Gender Eq. St., 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 8)
    - ASA USOC, 1994 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 9)
    - [Title IX Press Conference materials], 1995 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 10)
    - H.R. 2209/S.1311 -> Bill to establish Ntnl. Foundation on Physical Fitness + Sport, 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 11)
    - Atlanta Plus, 1995 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 12)
    - Amateur Sports Act, 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 13)
    - USOC/NCAA Task Force, 1995-2002 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 14)
    - Title IX Athletic Budgets + Wms. Sports, 1990-1994 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 15)
    - NWCA vs. Board of Education, 2002 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 16)
    - Law vs. NCAA, 1998 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 17)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1987-1994 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 18)
    - SUNY Albany, 1994-1995 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 19)
    - Studies: Wiestart article "Can gender equity find a place in commercialized college sports?", 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 20)
    - Studies: SAT gender gap (NCWGE), 1997 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 21)
    - Studies: CRS report, 1997 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 22)
    - Studies: Andrew Zimbalist- Economics of college sports, 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 23)
    - Studies: Indiana Law review article Title IX tug of war, 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 24)
    - Studies: lesbian sport fiction Joli Sandoz, 1993 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 25)
    - Studies: Title IX in intercollegiate athletics Baker and Botts, 1993 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 26)
    - Studies: University of Iowa gender equity project, 1996 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 27)
    - NCAA, 1997-1999 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 28)
    - [NCAA membership and participation], 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 29)
    - Gender equity studies and publications, 1984-1992 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 30)
    - NCAA - proposal 39, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 31)
    - NCAA battle, 1987 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 32)
    - NCAA cost reduction proposals, 1984-1990 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 33)
    - Athletic correspondence: gender equity proposals, 1983-1995 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 34)
    - Athletic correspondence: gender issues, 1990-1996 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 1)
    - Athletic correspondence: Title IX compliance bulletin for college athletics, 2000 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 2)
    - General college, 2002 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 3)
    - National coalition for girls and women in education, 1996 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 4)
    - NCAA: survey of student interests in athletics, sports and physical fitness, 1995 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 5)
    - Proposal 39 NCAA scholarship cuts, 1988 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 6)
    - Title IX the college board, 1996 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 7)
    - Amicus brief statement, 1996 January (Offsite-box 95, Folder 8)
    - Legislation Civil Rights Restoration Act, 1988 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 9)
    - Legislation - comparable worth, 1983 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 10)
    - Title IX NCAA seminars, 1995 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 11)
    - Legislation - gender equity in athletics disclosure act, 1995 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 12)
    - OCR clarification, 1995-2000 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 13)
    - Senate appropriation bill rider Pennsylvania letters, 1995 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 14)
    - Legislation - non-profit tax exempt bill funding of amateur sports, 1982 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 15)
    - Legislation, 1991-1996 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 16)
    - Title IX training manual draft, 1981 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 17)
    - USA Today, 1997 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 18)
    - [Articles], 1996 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 19)
    - Glass Ceiling Act, 1991 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 20)
    - USOC, 1987 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 21)
    - Women in intercollegiate sports study, 1974-2004 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 22)
    - [NCAA gender-equity study], 1992-1997 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 23)
    - NCAA T9 seminar (4 folders), 1997 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 24-27)
    - New York Human Rights Law (1 of 3 folders), 2005 (Offsite-box 95, Folder 28)
    - New York Human Rights Law (2 of 3 folders), 2005 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 1-2)
    - Sex equity programs/ organizations: Feminist majority foundation, 1993 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 3)
    - Sex equity programs/ organizations: feminist party, 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 4)
    - Sex equity programs/ organizations: Citizens for sport equity, 1986 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 5)
    - Sex equity programs/ organizations: Educators for athletic equity, 1985 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 6)
    - NY state task force women's issues, 1987 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 7)
    - Congressional caucus for women's issues, 1991 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 8)
    - Texas gender equity in sports conference, 1992 March (Offsite-box 96, Folder 9)
    - California civil rights initiative, 1996 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 10)
    - Dave Koerner articles, 1988 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 11)
    - Women's coaching/ equity programs, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 12)
    - Activism project, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 13)
    - Title IX advocacy project, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 14)
    - Long Island fund for girls, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 15)
    - Executive women's golf, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 16)
    - National women's political caucus, 1997 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 17)
    - Connecticut women's education and legal fund, 1997 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 18)
    - Title IX equity coalition of Fresno, circa 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 19)
    - Trial lawyers for public justice, 1999 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 20)
    - Trial lawyers for public justice - correspondence, 1997 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 21)
    - NCWGE: National coalition for women and girls in education, 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 22)
    - NCWGE: HR 4994, 2004 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 23)
    - NCWGE: Tucson, 2004-2005 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 24)
    - NOW love your body day, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 25)
    - NCSEE, 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 26)
    - National committee for pay equity, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 27)
    - White House women's office, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 28)
    - Texas civil rights project, 2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 29)
    - Ohio gender equity coalition, 1998 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 30)
    - National coalition for athletics equity/ fair play, 1998 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 31)
    - The president's council on physical fitness and sports strategic plan, 1994 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 32)
    - Pro bono students, 1994 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 33)
    - Minnesota coalition to promote women in athletic leadership, 1994 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 34)
    - National association for women in education, 1996 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 35)
    - LPGA girl scout program, 1987 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 36)
    - Non-revenue sports coalition - Title IX, 1994 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 37)
    - Target Title IX, 1992 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 38)
    - Michigan group, 1997 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 39)
    - AAUW/ NCWGE lists, 1998 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 40)
    - Advocacy committee (2 folders), 1993-2000 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 41-42)
    - Congressional testimonies (8 folders), 1985-1997 (Offsite-box 96, Folder 43-50)
    - Title IX hearings, 1995 May 9 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 1)
    - Congress testimonies, 1993 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 2)
    - Race discrimination committee, 1998-1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 3)
    - Congressional correspondence, 1992-1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 4)
    - NCAA correspondence, 1994 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 5)
    - Non-revenues to Congress Dick Aronson - NACGC, 1994 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 6)
    - US Department of Justice civil rights division, 1994 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 7)
    - Copies of Donna [Lopiano] speeches, 1997-1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 8)
    - Donna Lopiano - expert reports, 1997 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 9)
    - SHSAA rules: Title IX and SHSAA group, 1993-1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 10)
    - SHSAA rules: MIAA (Mass), 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 11)
    - SHSAA rules: transfer rules study, 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 12)
    - SHSAA rules: NC transferring (Carl Piepper), 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 13)
    - SHSAA rules: Workman - Illinois HSAA, 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 14)
    - SHSAA rules: SHSAA stuff, 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 15)
    - Angels in the infield, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 16)
    - AAUW: checklist, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 17)
    - AAUW: AAUW of Minnesota, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 18)
    - AAUW: A license for bias, 2000 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 19)
    - ACLU - general information, 1996 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 20)
    - Center for Effective Public Policy, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 21)
    - Center for the protection of athletes rights - legal help, 1995 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 22)
    - Citizenship through sports alliance, 2000 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 23)
    - CONGO (UN newsletter), 2000 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 24)
    - Fairness and accuracy in reporting, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 25)
    - Fair test, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 26)
    - G.R.E.A.T. Mitxi Witchger, 1997 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 27)
    - Gender equity project inc., 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 28)
    - Long Island fund for women and girls, 1999 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 29)
    - NWLC, 2000 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 30)
    - NCAA (2 folders), 2000 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 31-32)
    - GWS Title IX workshop [disassembled binder], 1994 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 33)
    - NAGWS Title IX toolbox [disassembled binder] (1 of 2), 1992 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 34)
      Includes two floppy disks.
    - NAGWS Title IX toolbox (2 of 2). Digital files, 1996-1997 (Digital folder MS3199, Folder Box97_F34)
      Contains digital files originally stored on floppy disks in Box 97 Folder 34. Format of files is Microsoft Word documents. Files include a Department of Education OCR report, press release, and summary of findings, a report titled "Title IX Activity Regarding Collegiate Athletic Programs in the Post-Civil Rights Restoration Act Era" by Diane Heckman, and a list of colleges that failed to respond to requests for EADA.
    - NCAA achieving gender equity guide [disassembled binder], circa 1998 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 35)
    - Women's Sports Experience advocacy articles, 1992-2004 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 36)
    - Attorney referral/ list response, 2000-2002 (Offsite-box 97, Folder 37)
    - Advocacy monthly reports [disassembled binder] (3 folders), 1990-1999 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 1-3)
    - Unbelievables, 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 4)
    - [L. Leotus Morrison speeches and presentations] (3 folders), 1971-1989 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 5-7)
    - NHL/ USA hockey diversity task force official program handbook [disassembled binder] (2 folders), 1999 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 8-9)
    - On equal ground surveys, 2002 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 10)
    - Title IX media coverage (2 folders), 2002 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 11-12)
    - NCAA gender equity study summary of results, 1997 April (Offsite-box 98, Folder 13)
    - NCAA gender equity report, 2001-2002 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 14)
    - Fordham sports law (2 folders), 2003 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 15-16)
    - University of Michigan Journal of Law Reform (2 folders), 2000-2001 (Offsite-box 98, Folder 17-18)
    - Gender equity journals, reports, and articles (8 folders), 1992-2006 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 1-8)
      Contains journals, reports, dissertations, and articles published by a variety of organizations, Foundations, and agencies, including the United States Department of Education, Amateur Athletic Foundation of Los Angeles, National Coalition for Women and Girls in Education (NCWGE), and NCAA.
    - WSF reports, 1989-2003 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 9)
    - WSF Title IX educational resource kit, 2005 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 10)
    - Florida Gender Equity Commission, 1993-1994 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 11)
    - California legislation, 1985-1997 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 12)
    - Florida legislation, 1993 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 13)
    - State legislation overview, 1998 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 14)
    - California legislation, 1997 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 15)
    - Washington State survey information, 1989 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 16)
    - Washington State legislation, 1989-1997 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 17)
    - Ohio legislation, 1987 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 18)
    - Pennsylvania legislation, 1982 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 19)
    - State legislation South Dakota, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 99, Folder 20)
    - Minnesota legislation, 1984-1990 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 1)
    - New York legislation, 1985 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 2)
    - New Hampshire gender equity legislation, 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 3)
    - State legislation Montana, 1986 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 4)
    - State legislation Hawaii, circa 1985 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 5)
    - Illinois legislation, 1998 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 6)
    - State legislation Michigan, 1976 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 7)
    - State of Texas legislation, 1996 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 8)
    - Virginia state legislation, 1992 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 9)
    - Wisconsin state legislation, circa 1990 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 10)
    - General advocacy correspondence (64 folders), 1994 January-1997 May (Offsite-box 100, Folder 11-74)
    - OCR - general, 1996-1998 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 75)
    - Investigator's manual analysis, 1990-1994 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 76)
    - Title IX investigator's manual correspondence for revisions, 1994 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 77)
    - Testimony and legislation - Civil Rights Restoration Act, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 78)
    - Civil Rights Restoration Act, 1987 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 79)
    - Summit thanks, 1997 (Offsite-box 100, Folder 80)
    - Title IX/ CCRA, 1987 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 1)
    - Testimony and legislation - Civil Rights Restoration Act part 2, 1984 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 2)
    - OCR FOIA requests, 1995-1998 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 3)
    - Diane Heckman - post Restoration Act activity lists, 1994-1998 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 4)
    - Diane Heckman - women in athletics Title IX and the OCR, 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 5)
    - Heckman's post Restoration Act activity, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 6)
    - [OCR], 1995 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 7)
    - Diane Heckman compilation, 1997-198 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 8)
    - Sex discrimination in the gym and classroom Heckman, 1996 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 9)
    - OCR letters/ cases, 1992-1996 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 10)
    - Civil Rights Act of 1984 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 11)
    - Title IX/ CRRA clips (3 folders), 1984-1986 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 12-14)
    - CCRA of 1985 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 15)
    - Right to Know Act, 1990 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 16)
    - Physical Education for Progress (PEP) Act - Sen. Ted Stevens (R-AL), 1999 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 17)
    - Educating America's Girls Act, 1999 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 18)
    - OCR Boston, 1991 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 19)
    - OCR Chicago, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 20)
    - OCR Cleveland, 1988 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 21)
    - FOIA national office, 1997 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 22)
    - OCR offices FOIA: Philadelphia, 1988-1989 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 23)
    - OCR offices FOIA: San Francisco, 1989 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 24)
    - OCR offices FOIA: Seattle, 1991 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 25)
    - Dallas, 1991 (Offsite-box 101, Folder 26)
    - Denver, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 1)
    - Kansas City, 1991 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 2)
    - New York - letters of finding, 1989-1991 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 3)
    - School report card surveys (52 folders), 2001-2002 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 4-55)
      Contains printed online survey results submitted on WSF "school report card" website evaluating school sports programs. Files are organized by state or territory.
    - Title IX (2 folders), 1996-2002 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 56-57)
    - Current Title IX (2 folders), 2002 (Offsite-box 102, Folder 58-59)
    - Correspondence (5 folders), 2000-2003 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 1-5)
    - Daniels et al. vs. School Board of Bevard County Florida (4 folders), 1997-1999 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 6-9)
    - Title IX and gender equity articles and clippings (2 folders), 2000-2003 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 10-11)
    - Title IX reports (5 folders), 2000-2003 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 12-16)
    - Court cases, 1999-2002 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 17)
    - OSHAA, 2003 (Offsite-box 103, Folder 18)
    - WSF report "Advocating for Gender Equality in Sport" by Donna Lopiano, 2002 May 15 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 1)
    - National Wrestling Coaches Association vs. Department of Education, 2004 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 2)
    - Ilyse Sternberg vs USA National Karate-do Federation, 2000 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 3)
    - Mason, et al. v. Minnesota State High School League (12 folders), 2004 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 4-15)
      Folder 4 includes enclosed CD.
    - NAGWS Title IX Toolbox [disassembled binder], 1992 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 16)
    - Photocopied news clippings [disassembled binder], 1992 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 17)
    - News clippings, 1997 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 18)
    - Articles, studies, memos, 1998 (Offsite-box 104, Folder 19)
    - Equity white paper, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 1)
    - NACWAA (National Association of Collegiate Women Athletics Administrators), 1991-1994 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 2)
    - NACWAA (National Association of Collegiate Women Athletics Administrators), 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 3)
    - NACWAA (National Association of Collegiate Women Athletics Administrators), 1993 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 4)
    - Big Ten equity, 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 5)
    - Gender equity task force, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 6)
    - NCAA gender equity survey, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 7)
    - NCAA women's committee, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 8)
    - Women, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 9)
    - WSF meetings - Denver, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 10)
    - Equity articles, 1993 January (Offsite-box 105, Folder 11)
    - Equity congressional hearing, 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 12)
    - Title IX (2 folders), 1989-1993 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 13-14)
    - Reading, 1991-1993 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 15)
    - Title IX, circa 1990 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 16)
    - Big East, 1992 November 10 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 17)
    - Collins/ Donovan (equity), 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 18)
    - HR 921, 1993 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 19)
    - Senator Moseley-Braun Equity in Athletics Disclosure Act, 1994 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 20)
    - Equity, 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 21)
    - Advocacy correspondence (3 folders), 1992-1999 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 22-24)
    - Clippings (2 folders), 1992 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 25-26)
    - NCAA Guide to Title IX and Intercollegiate Athletics second edition, 1991 (Offsite-box 105, Folder 27)
    - GAO Intercollegiate Athletics report, 1992 August (Offsite-box 105, Folder 28)
    - Title IX Athletics Investigator's Manual, 1990 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Department of Education publications, 1987-1992 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 2)
    - Intercollegiate Sports congressional hearings (2 folders), 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 3-4)
    - NACWAA newsletter (National Association of Collegiate Women Athletics Administrators), 1993 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 5)
    - The New Agenda session and issue reports (3 folders), 1983 November 3-6 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 6-8)
    - The New Agenda delegate handbook and conference materials [disassembled binder] (4 folders), 1983 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 9-12)
    - The New Agenda attendee background information [disassembled binder] (2 folders), 1983-1984 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 13-14)
    - The New Agenda issue I [disassembled binder], 1983 November 3-6 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 15)
    - The New Agenda issue II [disassembled binder], 1983 November 3-6 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 16)
    - The New Agenda II conference (3 folders), 1987 June 19-21 (Offsite-box 106, Folder 17-19)
    - Expanding Opportunities position paper, circa 2001 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 1)
    - Title IX/ gender equity cases, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 2)
    - Should football be scaled down, 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 3)
    - Title IX's interest and abilities issue: the smokescreen and the solutions, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 4)
    - OCR complaint forms, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 5)
    - OCR report - executive summary, 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 6)
    - Title IX Athletics Investigator's Manual (2 folders), 1990 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 7-8)
    - OCR full report (2 folders), 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 9-10)
    - Title IX: Capitol hill, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 11)
    - National coalition for athletics equity, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 12)
    - Independent women's forum, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 13)
    - Statements and testimonies (2 folders), 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 14-15)
    - Policy interpretation, 1979 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 16)
    - Gender equity study, 1992 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 17)
    - Gender equity study, 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 18)
    - Sexual harassment, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 19)
    - Achieving gender equity, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 20)
    - NCAA Title IX seminar, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 21)
    - NCAA revenues and expenses, 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 22)
    - Resources on cutting men's sports: compliance quiz, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 23)
    - Resources on cutting men's sports: NWLC position paper on men's sports, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 24)
    - Resources on cutting men's sports: position paper, circa 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 25)
    - Title IX checklist, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 26)
    - Positions on gender equity, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 27)
    - Common questions, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 28)
    - Myth busting, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 29)
    - Title IX chronology, 1997 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 30)
    - Title IX facts, 1999 (Offsite-box 109, Folder 31)
    - Worcester Women's History Project, 1999 (Offsite-box 110, Folder 1)
    - Press releases, 1995 (Offsite-box 110, Folder 2)
    - Gender equity resource forms, 1999 (Offsite-box 110, Folder 3)
    - Educational fact sheet, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 110, Folder 4)
    - Cheer leading, 1995 (Offsite-box 110, Folder 5)
    - The New Agenda issue IV [disassembled binder], 1983 November 3-6 (Offsite-box 120, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.C. Research records, 1973-2011; 11.5 Linear feet in 11.5 record cartons
    Subseries IV.C contains files documenting the research projects and publications of WSF. Documents include research planning files, proposals, correspondence, contracts, research reports and publications from non-WSF organizations, WSF research reports and additional publications, and conference materials. Research topics include the health of girls and women, college sports participation and funding, effects of sport on childhood and adolescent development, and Title IX in sport. Material dates from 1973-2011.